Had she vanished into thin air...Or was she never really there?
The Lady Vanishes is a mystery, thriller, comedy film directed by Anthony Page.
On the eve of World War II, zany heiress Amanda
Kelly travels by train to Switzerland.
While passing through Germany, she meets a sweet
elderly lady, who suddenly vanishes.
Distraught, she questions her fellow passengers who
claim that the woman was never there.
Unsure if it's all in her mind or if there's a more sinister plot afoot, Amanda
teams up with photographer Robert Condon to discover the truth.
Amanda Kelly, played by Cybill Shepherd.
Robert Condon, played by Elliott Gould.
Miss Froy, played by Angela Lansbury.
Dr. Egon Hartz, played by Herbert Lom.
Jeremy Charters, played by Arthur Lowe.
Caldicott, played by Ian Carmichael.
The Lady Vanishes is a 1979 British mystery comedy film directed by Anthony Page and written by George Axelrod, based on the screenplay of
1938's The Lady Vanishes by Sidney Gilliat and Frank Launder, in turn based on Ethel Lina White's 1936 novel The Wheel Spins.
The film stars Elliott Gould, Cybill Shepherd, Angela Lansbury,
Herbert Lom, Arthur Lowe and Ian Carmichael.
A remake of Alfred Hitchcock's 1938 film of the same name, the plot
follows two Americans travelling by train across 1939 Germany.
Together, they investigate the mysterious disappearance of an
English nanny also travelling on the train.
The remake's setting is essentially similar to Hitchcock's, but is openly set in
pre-Second World War Germany rather than in the original fictional country.
The Austrian fountain of Oberdrauburg by Hellmuth Marx is part of the setting.
In addition, both leads have their nationality changed from British to American.
The film was the last production by Hammer Films for 29
years, until Beyond the Rave (2008).
The film explores themes of spy, secret agent, search for witnesses, train.
The tone is intense and lighthearted and emotional.